guardiananytime.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | Guardian

Guardian is committed to protecting all of our customer's privacy rights. We comply with the privacy laws governing financial institutions and health insurers.

#### Customer Privacy Policy

Our Customer Privacy Policy describes our privacy commitment with respect to information we collect and disclose as a part of the customer relationship. Please note that we have updated our Customer Privacy Policy to make it more 'user friendly'. Guardian remains commited to ensuring that the confidential personal and financial information of our customers is protected. If you have any questions about our Privacy Policy please feel free to contact us at: Privacy Office, P.O. Box 780, Cooper Station, New York, NY 10276-0780

#### Park Avenue Securities Privacy Policy

For any questions on the Park Avenue Securities LLC Privacy Policy, please contact us at Park Avenue Securities LLC, Attn: Customer Service, 7 Hanover Square H4A, New York, NY 10004

HIPAA Privacy Policy

#### English

Our HIPAA Privacy Policy addresses the privacy of protected health information, or PHI, which applies to medical, dental, vision and prescription coverage.

#### Spanish

Nuestro principios de privacidad HIPAA aborda la privacidad de la información protegida de salud, o PHI, que se aplica a los servicios médicos, dentales, de visión y cobertura de medicamentos recetados.

## 

HIPAA FAQs

Our Privacy FAQs address detailed questions about The HIPAA Privacy Rule and how your accounts with Guardian are affected.

HIPAA Privacy FAQ – Participants

HIPAA Privacy FAQ – Plan Sponsors

The following forms are for submitting requests mentioned in the HIPAA Privacy Policy.

#### Authorization to disclose PHI

#### Confidential Communication Request

#### Request to Inspect & Copy PHI

#### Accounting of Disclosures Request

## 

Contact Us

If you have any additional questions related to privacy, feel free to contact us.

**At Guardian, we value every aspect of our relationship with you, and nothing could be more important to that relationship than maintaining your trust and confidence. We take our responsibility to protect your personal information very seriously. The purpose of this notice is to make you aware of our policies and procedures for collecting, disclosing, and safeguarding the information that our current and former customers provide to us.**

## 

We collect the personal information of our customers from the following sources:

  * Applications or other forms, such as policies, where we obtain items such as your name, date of birth, etc;
  * Your transactions with us and our affiliates, such as premium payments;
  * Consumer reporting agencies and other similar sources relating to creditworthiness; and
  * Our Internet websites, where we capture items that you provide when you fill out forms.

## 

To better serve you, the law provides for the disclosure of certain information we collect as follows:

  * With affiliates to administer your policy or account, or to give you information about other products and services that may be of interest to you. We may also share non-credit-related information with affiliates to develop marketing programs. We may do this without obtaining prior authorization and the law does not allow customers to restrict these disclosures.
  * We may also share your information with our affiliates about your transactions and experiences with us, such as payment history.
  * With your agent, broker, or representative in order to service your policy or account.
  * With non-affiliates in order to administer your policy or account or to administer our business.
  * With non-affiliates with whom we have a joint marketing agreement, such as other financial companies, in order to send you information about products and services. We require that all non-affiliates keep your information confidential. We do not share your information with non-affiliates for any reason other than those stated above.

**We may also share your information if the law permits or requires sharing, such as during the investigations of public authorities.**

**IMPORTANT: WHY YOU ARE RECEIVING THIS NOTICE**

**We are required by federal law to provide this notice upon the establishment of our relationship with you; furthermore, we must provide this notice annually so long as you have a policy, contract or other type of account with one or more of the entities listed in the Guardian Corporate Family. This requirement applies regardless of whether or not we share any of your information.**

**CONFIDENTIALITY AND SECURITY**

**Under federal law, certain disclosures may require us to allow you to “opt-out” (i.e. allow you the option to prohibit certain types of information sharing). If we are considering a disclosure that would trigger your right to opt-out, we will allow you to do so before your information is shared.**

**Any health information collected by us requires you to complete a separate authorization. We will not disclose your health information to anyone without your authorization, unless the law permits or requires us to do so.**

Access to your personal information is restricted to only those Guardian employees who need it to perform the services required of your policy or account. We have physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable federal and state regulations to keep your personal information safe. If you decide to end your relationship with a member of the Guardian Corporate Family, or if your policy or account becomes inactive for some other reason, we will continue to treat and safeguard your information as described in this notice.

The accuracy of your information is important to us. You have the right to access and to seek correction of your information. You also have the right to request a record of any subsequent disclosures of your information. You may contact us at the address below to receive more information regarding these rights or to receive a more detailed explanation of our privacy policies.

_Visit us at **http://www.guardianlife.com/Privacy-Policy** _ _where Group planholders may also access Guardian’s HIPAA Privacy Policy; paper copies are available upon request. We ask that Group planholders share this information with their plan participants_

**The Guardian Life Insurance Company of America** Privacy Office, P.O. Box 780, Cooper Station, New York, NY 10276-0780
